BON APPÉTIT, YOUR MAJESTY
I see you are here.
What is taking her so long?
Everyone.
We must go and tell His Majesty.
Or she is going to die!
But His Highness has become unconscious.
This is beyond anything we can do.
We should not get involved rashly.
That is exactly how
the former chief royal cook met his end.
They will make up crimes
she did not commit if they must.
Then are you saying
we just sit back and do nothing?
How could you all be like this?
If you will just sit here and do nothing,
I will go on my own.
I will go to His Majesty.
No.
You stay here.
I will go.
Cook Maeng.
Cook Maeng…
Fine. I might as well.
I will come as well.
No, I will lead the way.
Let us try.
Yes, I will join too.
-Eunuch Yoon.
-Greetings.
Eunuch Yoon!
-Our miss…
-What is going on?
Our miss is…
How pleased will she be
when she sees this?
GOCHO
I cannot wait to see the look on her face.
If she jumps into my arms like last time…
Thank you so much!
I believe this was the stance.
This time,
I will not fall over.
Your Majesty!
Your Majesty.
Yes.
-Is she here?
-The chief royal cook
was tortured and imprisoned.
The chief royal cook was tortured?
What on earth are you saying?
Grand Prince Jinmyeong
is on the verge of death.
Jinmyeong?
He fell ill after he ate
the chief royal cook's chicken dish,
so the Queen Dowager is furious.
She interrogated
the chief royal cook herself
and then threw her into prison.
-Your Majesty!
Cook Yeon.
Open the door immediately.
Your Majesty, with all due respect…
How dare you?
Open the door right this instant!
I wish I could,
but Her Royal Highness took the key.
What did you say?
Commander.
Break down this door!
Yes, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty.
I am sure you have heard by now.
QUEEN DOWAGER JAHYEON
YI HEON'S STEPMOTHER
My son Jinmyeong
ate the food that wench made
and now lingers on the brink of death.
What in the world are you saying?
I also ate the chicken
the chief royal cook prepared.
That is why I find it
even more suspicious.
What?
Are you implying
that I was behind all this?
If only
I had questioned it
when you were so kind to my son,
if I had prevented it,
then perhaps this would not
have happened to my Jinmyeong.
Why would I do such a thing
when I have no reason to fear him?
If something unfortunate
were to happen to you,
Jinmyeong would take the throne,
and maybe that is what you fear!
I dare you to say that again.
At last, you show your true colors.
Say it again!
Hand over the key.
It is a royal command.
You will not have it
as long as I am breathing.
Kill me.
I said it was a royal command!
Your Majesty!
Please. Your Majesty.
Your Majesty.
Calm down.
You must not do this.
What are you all doing?
Cover her immediately!
Put the sword down.
You're not helping me by doing this.
You know better than anyone
that I wouldn't do such a thing.
So…
So put down the sword,
and please prove my innocence.
You must never
become a tyrant.
COURSE N° 10 JOSEON RESTAURANT
If we must become political enemies
just because we are blood-related…
then it is only right
that I put an end to it all right now.
Your Majesty.
I know what happens here.
I know the future.
If you use that sword now,
everything will get out of control.
The situation is already past
the point of control.
No.
Nothing has happened yet.
Put down the sword.
And no matter what happens,
you must restrain yourself.
You must stand strong.
Please leave. Now.
If I leave now…
you will die.
If you do this, everyone will die!
Do you want me to hang myself right now?
Will you believe me if I do that?
Believe me.
To think that you, Queen Dowager,
who always seemed on my side
and embraced me with your kind grace,
had been harboring such a different heart.
I now realize what truly lies beneath
your benevolent facade.
I, myself,
will get to the bottom of this incident.
If you torture the chief royal cook again
before the truth is out,
there will be hell to pay.
Very well.
However, if something
were to happen to Jinmyeong before then,
I will see to it that the wench pays.
If you wish to punish her,
you will have to dethrone me first.
Your Majesty.
You must have been scared.
It must have been hard.
You must stay strong.
Okay.
You have to remember
what I said.
All right.
I will not forget it.
Your Royal Highness,
it appears His Majesty
has set forth plans in secret.
Brother.
How could you utter such disloyal words?
I did not tell you
to spare you from the concern,
but Principal Drafter Yi
of the Office of Royal Decrees
is looking for the draft of the record
that details how the deposed queen passed.
The draft of the historical record
that details
how His Majesty's mother passed?
If His Majesty is looking for the draft
with the knowledge
that we were involved in her death,
would it not be
so that he can oust our Han family
that put him on the throne?
I believe this is connected
to what happened
to Grand Prince Jinmyeong.
No.
Brother, think back
to the Muin Literati Purge.
OPPRESSION OF SARIM FACTION SCHOLARS
IN THE 4TH YEAR OF YEONHUIGUN'S REIGN
His Majesty is someone who would
make pretenses to exile individuals.
He is not one to scheme or plot.
And to use poison of all things?
This is not His Majesty's doing.
Not to mention, His Majesty has changed
since the chief royal cook came here.
He has become a different person.
Will you believe me only after
the other princes fall unconscious?
The only one to escape this crisis
will be the idiotic Grand Prince Jesan.
Jesan…
Grand Prince Jesan…
GRAND PRINCE JESAN
SUPERINTENDENT OF SAONGWON
Her Grace Consort Kang
has contributed a great deal to our plan.
What happened to Grand Prince Jinmyeong
is unfortunate,
but the Grand Royal Queen Dowager
and her Han relatives
will not be able to avoid
clashing with His Majesty.
If His Majesty
eradicates the Han family
that has long served him,
that will be our chance
to claim the cause to oust a tyrant
and turn our swords against him.
Your Highness.
Why are you allowing
that enemy Yi Jang-gyun to live?
He led the men who massacred
our tutors and brothers
who were in hiding during the last purge.
Regardless,
he still has a role to play.
We still
need him alive.
I do hope Grand Prince Jinmyeong
does not regain consciousness.
It does not matter now.
His Majesty and the chief royal cook
will not be able to avoid
this arrow of fate.
I understand why the Queen Dowager
caused a scene out of fury,
but Cook Yeon had no reason
to harm the Grand Prince
she had just met today.
Find out if Grand Prince Jinmyeong
ate anything else
after the meal with me,
whom he met, and where he went.
Look into every detail and report to me.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty, please take a look at this.
What is this?
It is the log from the dispensary.
We also ate the chicken
His Majesty and His Highness ate,
but none of us suffered in any way.
I even ate an extra leg in secret,
and I am perfectly fine.
I ate some of the skin,
but nothing happened to me.
My problem is that I have too much energy.
The ingredients are clearly not to blame.
The royal physician
will check every ingredient.
Inform me immediately
if anything else comes to mind.
Your Majesty,
I spoke to those at the royal kitchen,
and those at Naeuiwon, Royal Clinic,
carefully inspected all the ingredients
used in the roasted ogolgye,
and they did not find anything unusual.
I knew it.
You can see that I am fine.
Could Grand Prince Jinmyeong
be suffering from something else?
What makes you think that?
The royal physician said
his symptoms only arise
when one ingests poison,
but he did not take anything poisonous.
How about you visit
the quarters of the Queen Dowager
and check on His Highness?
How is he?
GRAND PRINCE JINMYEONG
YI HEON'S HALF-BROTHER
Your Royal Highness.
I apologize.
What a disaster this is.
How could the heavens be so cruel?
His Majesty the King has arrived.
Is he recovering?
We are searching for a cure.
I apologize for the delay, Your Majesty.
What could have possibly
made you come to my quarters,
which is usually
the least of your concerns?
You speak out of line,
Your Royal Highness.
Your Majesty.
What brings you here?
The royal physician examined all the food
Grand Prince Jinmyeong consumed that day
but did not find
anything unusual about it.
Is what His Majesty said true?
Yes, Your Royal Highness. It is true.
I also looked into
who Grand Prince Jinmyeong met
in the last fortnight,
but I was told he was always here with you
under your care.
That is why I came to see you.
That is why
I blame the food he ate that day.
What are those medicinal herbs?
They are herbs
used in the restorative medicine
that His Highness takes regularly
due to his poor health.
Restorative medicine?
What is that doing here?
Grand Prince Jesan, the Superintendent
of Saongwon, Office of Royal Meals,
personally sends the herbs
every fortnight.
Then I inspect the contents here
and have them sent to Naeuiwon
to prepare the medicine to be brewed.
I must take them with me.
I will inspect them myself.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Chang-seon.
With all due respect, Your Majesty,
I doubt there will be
anything wrong with it.
Do you really think Grand Prince Jesan
would send the wrong herbs?
Your Majesty.
The reason
Grand Prince Jinmyeong's life is at risk
is because of that
wretched chief royal cook.
Your Royal Highness.
Mind your words.
If word of this
were to spread outside the palace,
what would that do
to the reputation of the royal family?
Your Royal Highness.
Are you all right?
I am so afraid of His Majesty.
I…
do not fear him anymore.
The day my son dies,
the chief royal cook and His Majesty
will both pay dearly.
-Your Royal Highness.
Your Royal Highness,
it is I, Court Lady Kim.
What is it?
The Grand Royal Queen Dowager
has sent me to get the key to the prison
where the chief royal cook is being held.
The Grand Royal Queen Dowager sent you?
Yes, Your Royal Highness.
Does something concern you, Your Majesty?
What am I to do
if nothing is wrong with the herbs either?
Cook Yeon is not well.
To think that she must be
suffering in that cold prison
weighs on my heart.
I cannot stand it.
I sent Eunuch Yoon
to check on her
in the morning and evening,
and she is doing well and staying strong,
saying that it is where she stayed
when she first came to the palace.
You need not worry too much, Your Majesty.
What do you mean it is where she stayed?
I am talking about the prison
you had specially arranged for her
when she first came to the palace,
Your Majesty.
Think of it as a basic rule
to survive in the palace.
I will prepare
a special residence for you.
Do you still remember such a thing?
That is not like you.
However,
things are different now.
If I leave her be,
her life will not be worth living.
What must I do?
What must I do to save you?
Where on earth is my Mangunrok?
How did I end up in Joseon
only to suffer such hardships?
I want to go home so badly.
The Grand Royal Queen Dowager has arrived.
Over here. I'm in here.
I thought you would be struggling,
but I see you have managed to adapt
even in this place.
Gil-geum and I stayed here for a while,
so I'm used to it.
I will ask you just one thing.
Did you truly try to kill
the Grand Prince?
No.
Please don't tell me
you also believe that.
Then did His Majesty put you up to it?
What are you saying?
You know what he's like.
If he wanted someone dead,
he'd do it himself.
You must keep your wits sharp.
His Majesty is under suspicion
because of you.
If this continues,
he will end up in grave danger.
His Majesty will be in danger?
All kinds of malicious rumors
are running rampant throughout the palace.
They say Grand Prince Jinmyeong
is on the verge of death
because you, the chief royal cook,
poisoned his food.
They say His Majesty's judgment
has been clouded
because he keeps
the gwinyeo cook too close to him.
If you fail to prove your innocence,
you will be tortured at Uigeumbu,
State Tribunal,
for attempting to murder a grand prince
and die amid great suffering.
So much so that you would
want to take your own life.
If I get you out of here,
can you find evidence
to prove your innocence?
If you do,
I promise to find evidence,
no matter what.
If you fail to prove your innocence…
you must put an end to it
yourself.
It's a real silver dagger.
I will give you three days.
You must
find evidence.
Yes, I will.
Is that His Majesty's natgeotsang,
daytime meal?
-Oh my goodness!
-Miss!
-My goodness. What happened?
-Oh my goodness.
-Miss!
-My gosh!
-Look how haggard you have become!
Just a moment!
I'll explain everything later.
Let me serve the natgeotsang first.
Sure.
Cook Maeng,
put the rest of the jeon on the table.
Cook Sim and Cook Min,
get the other side dishes.
-Okay.
-Hurry!
Your Majesty, your natgeotsang is ready.
I do not want it. Take it away.
Your Majesty, I told you many times.
You shouldn't skip your meals.
Chief Royal Cook?
Am I hearing things again?
Your Majesty.
Cook Yeon.
-Your Majesty.
I missed you so much.
How did you get out?
All kinds of malicious rumors
are running rampant throughout the palace.
They say His Majesty's judgment
has been clouded
because he keeps
the gwinyeo cook too close to him.
Your Majesty.
You don't seem to understand,
so let me make it very clear.
There are misunderstandings
and absurd rumors going around the palace
because you keep hugging
and kissing a woman you don't even like.
I'll explain everything
while you have your--
What are you doing?
That was
for the woman I cherish the most.
That was my kiss.
Try it.
Try this too.
Very well.
This too.
Cook Yeon.
Eat with me today.
Pardon?
Your Majesty, that'd be inappropriate.
Are you talking back to me?
No, but…
Then eat.
Go on.
Okay.
You appear to have become rather haggard.
Please make sure to eat your meals.
I could say the same about you.
Tell me.
How did you get out?
The Grand Royal Queen Dowager released me.
After you eat,
we must uncover the truth together.
Uncover the truth
together?
Yes.
The Grand Royal Queen Dowager let me out
on the condition
that I do that within three days.
What kind of silly promise is that?
It's more serious than you think.
Forget what you promised my grandmother.
Do you think I would let you die?
Your Majesty.
Do you really like me?
Do you really have feelings for me?
You should eat.
Her Royal Highness
is concerned that foul rumors about us
are going around the palace.
From now on,
you can't do what you did to me earlier.
In that case,
tell me in detail
what I can and cannot do.
Do you really not know?
You can't do anything
without my permission, okay?
Be more specific.
Well…
Hugging me wherever you please,
calling me out at night,
getting drunk and kissing me,
or doing what you did earlier…
Anyway, you can't do any of that.
How very silly.
Silly?
I'm being serious here,
and you call it silly?
Yes.
Do you want some rice punch?
No.
Don't mind me,
who focuses on silly things.
Do not be like that.
Here.
Drink it.
Go on.
The cooks have gotten much better.
The old hag released the chief royal cook?
KANG MOK-JU
FOURTH JUNIOR CONSORT, YI HEON'S CONCUBINE
She must have gone senile.
She has only earned
three more days to live.
Three days, you say?
Will the chief royal cook
find evidence first,
or will Grand Prince Jinmyeong die first?
I guess it would not be so bad
to stand by and watch.
If you have something on your mind,
do tell.
Why did you release the chief royal cook
when you should have tortured
the truth out of her?
Release her?
Do you still not see
what His Majesty is thinking?
He is searching for an excuse
to exterminate our Han family.
We cannot be sure of that.
Whatever the case, we need His Majesty
to remain on the throne.
That is of grave importance to our family.
Just wait and see
what the chief royal cook will do
if she cannot find evidence
within three days.
DAY 1 OF THE INVESTIGATION
Look at this.
Ginkgo nuts, chestnuts, jujube.
None of the ingredients in your dish
were unfamiliar to Grand Prince Jinmyeong.
Then could it be the butter…
-I mean, could it be the suyu?
-Suyu?
After eating it, did he seem dizzy
or develop any rashes?
I am not certain about rashes.
Can eating a lot of ginseng make you ill?
I used ginseng to cook the meal.
Eating too much of it
can cause headaches or sleeplessness,
but it would not cause one
to become unconscious.
I tasted the ingredients
of Jinmyeong's medicine.
What is the one that tastes rather odd?
Could that be musk?
It was not musk.
They were small and round,
almost bean-like,
with a foul taste.
Your Majesty.
It is normal for restorative medicine
to taste bitter and foul.
The bitterness was unlike
any of the other ingredients.
DAY 2 OF THE INVESTIGATION
Your Majesty.
What did the maids who cleaned out
Grand Prince Jinmyeong's chamber pot say?
They said there was nothing unusual
about his fecal matter.
I apologize for the bad news,
Your Majesty.
My gosh, miss. You are finally back.
What should I do?
No matter how hard I look,
there's no hope.
It is the second day already.
Anyway, what is in here?
Ingredients of Grand Prince Jinmyeong's
restorative medicine and food records.
I see.
Let me see. Goodness.
They are incredibly precious herbs.
What could this smell be?
Why? Does it smell strange?
Miss, this smells of rats.
They must have nibbled on them.
Come on, that's ridiculous.
They wouldn't have let rats
eat His Highness' medicine.
This is definitely
the smell of rat droppings.
Is it?
It does smell revolting.
DAY 3 OF THE INVESTIGATION
So Grand Prince Jinmyeong
has never been picky about food?
That is right.
He is not a picky eater like His Majesty,
and he has never suffered
such a high fever before.
Maybe the chicken dish
did not cause the illness after all.
Other than my food, the only thing he had
was his usual restorative medicine.
Chief Royal Cook.
You must hurry to His Majesty's quarters.
His Majesty has suddenly collapsed.
His Majesty?
Your Majesty,
the chief royal cook is here.
Your Majesty, are you all right?
You are here.
Do not cause a fuss.
Is he all right?
His Majesty has had
a lot on his mind lately,
and that seems to have exhausted him.
Wait.
Does His Majesty have a fever?
How did you know that?
Aren't his symptoms similar
to those of Grand Prince Jinmyeong?
Now that you mention it, it is strange.
Why do I have
the same symptoms as Jinmyeong?
You tasted the medicinal herbs
during the investigation.
If you have a fever like the Grand Prince,
then his illness…
Could it be related to
one of the medicinal herbs?
To a medicinal herb?
Yes.
His Majesty said
one of them had a foul taste,
and Gil-geum said
it smelled like rat droppings.
But musk and milkvetch root
do not have a foul taste,
and while the other medicinal herbs
might smell musty,
they don't smell like rat droppings.
The smell of rat droppings
and a foul taste…
Could it be…
oryeongji?
ORYEONGJI: MEDICINAL HERBS
MADE FROM DRIED FLYING SQUIRREL DROPPINGS
Oryeongji?
What is that?
In China, there are flying squirrels
that glide using their skin
stretched between their limbs.
The feces of flying squirrels
that have been prepared for medicinal use
is called oryeongji.
By "feces," you mean…
Rat droppings?
That is why it tasted so disgusting.
Then does the medicine contain oryeongji?
I will have to check to be sure,
but I do not believe oryeongji is included
in His Highness' medicinal herbs.
Also, oryeongji is not a poison
but a valuable medicinal ingredient.
Then is it not that either?
Your Majesty, did you eat anything
other than the ginseng porridge
from the royal kitchen today?
What else would I have eaten?
Ginseng.
When oryeongji is ingested with ginseng,
everything changes.
How so?
It becomes a sangbanyak.
In other words, poison.
Poison?
Then could it cause death?
Yes. If oryeongji and ginseng
are consumed together,
it causes chills and a fever.
If consumed in excess,
it could threaten one's life.
Then isn't His Majesty's life
in danger too?
Even if oryeongji were included
in the Grand Prince's medicine,
His Majesty only tasted it,
so his symptoms will disappear in time.
That's a relief.
If Jinmyeong is in such a critical state
because he ate a chicken dish with ginseng
and the medicine with oryeongji…
Is there an antidote?
Yes, Your Majesty.
I can make an antidote.
However, it will take some time.
In that case, confirm the facts
and promptly make
an antidote for Jinmyeong.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Someone
poisoned him by cunning means.
The culprit must be someone
who knows that oryeongji and ginseng
become a poison when eaten together.
Indeed.
Chang-seon.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Send the Chief Royal Secretary to Naeuiwon
and have him identify
who tampered with Jinmyeong's medicine.
Yes, Your Majesty.
My uncle manages the medicinal herbs,
so who would tamper with them?
The culprit
must be someone close by.
Think carefully, Your Majesty.
Grand Prince Jinmyeong
will wake up soon, won't he?
It is all thanks to you.
I'm relieved.
Your Majesty, you should lie back down.
Come on.
Your Majesty.
I told you not to do this
without my permission.
Let us allow just this.
But if someone were to come in…
It is to cure my headache.
Just for a while.
Stay here just a while.
Greetings, Chief Royal Secretary.
Name every person who handled
Grand Prince Jinmyeong's medicine.
Yes, my lord.
A female physician named Eo Yeo-bun
was in charge of
the Grand Prince's medicine,
but no one has seen her in days.
FEMALE PHYSICIAN EO YEO-BUN
BREWED MEDICINE
What?
The one who tampered with the medicine
is the female physician?
Yes, Your Majesty.
She added oryeongji to the medicinal herbs
and sent it
to the Queen Dowager's quarters.
However, Your Majesty,
I went to look for her
upon hearing that she had gone missing,
but she had already fled.
Send the palace guards
to find her immediately.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Can we find her by tomorrow?
The time I promised Her Royal Highness
is almost up.
Do not worry.
We found the culprit.
Your innocence has now been proven.
I will speak with my grandmother.
Why do you think
the female physician did it?
In such matters as this,
there is always one who commands it.
We must find the physician
if we are to find out who that is.
How can we find someone
who went into hiding?
Finding someone in hiding?
Gong-gil is better at that
than any slave hunter.
Find this physician.
You must find her tonight.
-Yes, sir.
Your Grace, a message has arrived
from Grand Prince Jesan's residence.
Im Song-jae came to meet His Highness,
as he is the Superintendent of Saongwon,
claiming to be looking for
a missing female physician.
-What?
-That is not all.
He used that as an excuse
to search His Highness' residence.
Is it possible he has caught on?
I believe His Highness is under suspicion.
Chu-wol.
We must silence that female physician.
Take care of it.
Yes, Your Grace.
FORBIDDEN
My lady.
You are here.
It must have been an arduous journey.
Is it all over?
Can I return to Naeuiwon now?
Yes.
However, we must go somewhere else first.
Where is that?
The afterlife.
How dare you, you lowly jester.
So you are the wench
who killed my sister Ok-dan.
What are you talking about?
She had this in her hand when she died.
It is your weapon.
I cannot see clearly because it is dark.
Oh, you are one nasty woman.
You wench.
You look a complete mess
with your hair in disarray.
This damned wench.
A rotten wench like you should go to hell!
You speak with a tongue
as foul as your lowly birth.
I will silence
that vulgar mouth of yours for good.
Do you not fear the heavens?
Very well.
This is the day you die.
Why did you kill my sister?
Did the king command it
after he took her for chaehong?
His Majesty?
You fool.
Tell the truth!
Why? Do you want revenge?
So you were the one
who has been trying to kill His Majesty.
Tell me who ordered you to kill her.
Was it Kang Mok-ju or the king?
Your tongue will be the death of you.
This is where you die.
I see it was Consort Kang's order.
All the court ladies at Jahongwon…
die when their use is done.
Who says so?
Who gets to decide that?
Why?
Why did you kill her?
Shall I tell you the truth before you die?
Your sister incurred
Her Grace's displeasure
because she tried to win
His Majesty's favor.
It must have been
for her starving brother.
You took someone's life
over such a trivial matter?
She died because of you.
You do not deserve to be called humans!
Die!
Look.
Wake up.
Do you hear me?
Please spare me.
I am sorry.
Tell the truth, and I will spare you.
Did you tamper with
Grand Prince Jinmyeong's medicine?
Yes.
I was scared of Her Grace Consort Kang,
so I had no choice.
The person behind it all
was Consort Kang, not the king.
It was that sly wench.
The truth is,
there is someone behind Her--
Who is there?
I got rid of the female physician,
but Gong-gil was incredibly skilled,
so I was unable to take care of Chu-wol.
Were you injured?
It is nothing serious, Your Highness.
I see a mere jester
possesses great skill.
I will have Consort Kang
take care of Chu-wol.
Go to the butchers' village
and get Yi Jang-gyun right away.
Yes, Your Highness.
No matter how much we torture her,
she insists she had nothing to do
with Grand Prince Jinmyeong's incident.
Look up and face me, criminal.
I heard you were
the inspector court lady at Jahongwon.
Did Consort Kang put you up to it?
No, Your Majesty.
Her Grace knows nothing of it.
I had a personal grudge,
and I did everything on my own.
Please believe me, Your Majesty.
-This is not getting anywhere.
-Please believe me.
I will ask Consort Kang myself.
Your Majesty!
Your Majesty.
Chu-wol.
His Majesty the King has--
Your Majesty.
Was it you?
What do you mean, Your Majesty?
Not only did your trusted court lady
hide the physician who was involved
in Grand Prince Jinmyeong's poisoning,
but she was caught
trying to kill her as well.
Do you still plan to continue
to feign ignorance?
I know nothing about that.
Why did you do it?
How can there be a reason
when I know nothing of the matter?
Do you not believe me?
What do you gain from doing this?
I gain nothing.
Actually,
you came to see me
after a long while to wrongly accuse me,
so perhaps that is a gain on my part.
Do you truly…
wish to die?
Your Majesty.
If you wish to punish me,
bring forth the evidence.
You committed a grave sin worthy of death.
The least you should be doing
is pleading for your life.
But very well.
I shall bring evidence.
GANGNYEONGJEON
How did you know?
I heard you told Gong-gil
that if he had the jesters
stir up a scene under the guise
of searching for the physician
while keeping an eye on Consort Kang,
he would be able to locate the physician.
Gil-geum was attacked
during the competition
against the cooks of the royal kitchen,
and Gong-gil saved her.
He said the attacker
was dressed like a court lady,
and I thought if anyone here
was brazen enough to do that,
it would be Her Grace Consort Kang.
Are you saying something similar
happened then too?
Yes.
Your Majesty, your medicine is here.
Your Majesty.
This is cheongyeolyak,
which will eliminate the toxic effects
of oryeongji and ginseng.
CHEONGYEOLYAK:
HERBAL MEDICINE TO COUNTER A FEVER
CHOI MAL-IM
KING'S SENIOR COURT LADY
What about Grand Prince Jinmyeong?
Now that Your Majesty
has taken the medicine,
we will be serving it
to Grand Prince Jinmyeong.
I must be there to witness it.
Your Majesty,
you must rest
and recover from the effects.
I am fine.
Come with me.
Yes.
His Majesty the King has arrived.
Your Majesty.
The royal physician
has prepared an antidote.
-Cheongyeolyak.
-Yes.
It will help bring down
the excessively high fever.
Hurry and give Jinmyeong the antidote.
Yes, Your Royal Highness.
Grand Prince Jinmyeong.
Do you feel better?
This is such a relief.
I am so glad.
He is better at last.
Grand Prince Jinmyeong!
What is the matter?
Grand Prince!
What is happening?
He is having a seizure!
Grand Prince Jinmyeong.
-Grand Prince.
-His pulse is fast and frail.
His body lacks the nutrition and energy
to take the medicine.
Prepare another medicine
to treat him immediately!
What good is making more medicine
when he cannot even swallow?
-Grand Prince Jinmyeong.
-Grand Prince!
-Grand Prince.
-Oh dear.
Could it be because…
The reason the antidote isn't working
is because he hasn't been eating, right?
Yes. You could say that.
I will prepare some food to restore
Grand Prince Jinmyeong's energy.
Are you planning to flee?
Queen Dowager.
The royal physician
confirmed Jinmyeong's state
was caused by a sangbanyak.
The female physician
who was involved has died,
but we apprehended a Jahongwon court lady
who tried to kill that physician.
So why do you still blame
the chief royal cook?
Grandmother.
The court lady is being interrogated,
so we will soon find out
who was behind it.
That is right.
If the chief royal cook wanted to flee,
she would not have come here at all.
Go ahead.
-Your Majesty!
-It is a royal command.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Jinmyeong.
Please come to your senses, Jinmyeong.
If I'm right,
Grand Prince Jinmyeong
is showing symptoms of hypoglycemic shock.
In other words, malnutrition.
I need to make a highly concentrated
nourishing dish that's easy to consume.
ROYAL KITCHEN
Attention, everyone!
-Chief Royal Cook!
-Miss! We were so worried about you.
What happened?
Sorry, Gil-geum. I'll explain later.
We're going to make a nourishing dish.
A nourishing dish?
What kind and with what?
Carp? Eel?
The dish is called "restaurant."
-"Resto…"
-"Restaro"?
Res… What is it called again?
There's no time, so we must hurry.
Gil-geum, I need you to make
gourd-shaped rice cakes with white rice.
Cook Maeng,
please make sujebi dough with wheat flour.
-Okay.
-Very well.
We are making a nourishing dish.
-Cook Min.
-Okay!
What shall I do?
Can you get me the ox feet soup we made
for the seoksura, evening meal?
-Okay.
-What about me?
Can you go to the storage in Naeuiwon
and get licorice, angelica root,
cheongung root, and velvet antler?
Sure.
Okay, nice.
What kind of dish is this restoran?
It's a nourishing dish that got its name
from the French word "restaurer,"
meaning "to restore."
We're making the Joseon version.
Oh, it is a Prance-style restoran.
So it is not an ordinary sujebi,
hand-pulled dough.
It's nice and thick.
It is as thick as a sauce.
You know so much now.
This is a velouté sauce.
Blatty sauce?
No, blotty sauce.
-Velouté sauce.
-Velouté.
-Velou…
-Give me that.
The chief royal cook has arrived.
I apologize for the delay.
Please help him sit up so he can eat.
How can I trust what you made
and give it to my son?
What is this?
It's a Joseon-style restaurant
with gourd-shaped rice cakes and sujebi.
Joseon-style "restoran"?
Gourd-shaped rice cakes?
How is this nourishing?
Rice cakes and sujebi
made with wheat flour
are rapidly digested
and absorbed into the body,
so they can be fattening
to ordinary people.
But Grand Prince Jinmyeong
is malnourished,
and this is exactly
what he needs right now.
The broth is made with ingredients
with invigorating properties,
including ox feet, velvet antler,
and cheongung root.
Very well. I get it.
All right.
Queen Dowager,
feed it to the Grand Prince.
Your Royal Highness.
I do not trust her.
If you do not trust her,
I will taste the food myself.
Your Majesty.
Your Majesty, it is not customary
for the king to taste the food first.
What better way is there
to ease the Queen Dowager's doubts?
Your Majesty, you cannot do it.
I would also like to taste the food
the chief royal cook prepared.
Your Majesty, I will taste the food.
No.
What are you doing?
You taste the food.
Your Majesty.
The broth is thick and rich.
The natural flavors of the ingredients
are flowing through my body.
I suddenly feel energized.
Queen Dowager, give it to him.
Just one bite.
Open up.
Look.
The spasms are subsiding.
Jinmyeong.
Mother.
My goodness.
His pulse is stabilizing.
This is unbelievable.
Thank goodness.
I'm so relieved.
The heavens helped us.
That is it.
There you go.
Are you all right?
Yes.
The sudden release of tension
made my legs weak.
I'm so relieved.
I was really worried.
You have been through a lot lately.
You have too.
You were ill and stressed out.
It must've been rough.
I appreciate the sentiment.
Come to Unyeongjeong
at the nineteenth hour.
There is something I wish to show you.
Okay.
What?
What are you going to show me?
Well,
you will see for yourself.
Okay.
Is it Mangunrok?
Did he find it?
Is this it?
Yes, this is it!
I found it on the way here.
Thank you! Thank you so much!
I understand
how desperately you seek this book,
so I will find it for you by any means.
I said it was a royal command!
Your Majesty!
You must have been scared.
You must stay strong.
But
what's wrong with me?
It's weird.
My heart aches.
All that was done came to nothing now.
It seems things have taken
an unexpected turn, Your Highness.
There is no need to be so pessimistic.
Once a rift forms,
it is hard to fill in.
Consort Kang did her part.
What do you mean by that?
I am saying
she has laid the groundwork well.
And she will also see to the rest herself.
Let us meet in the evening.
There is something I wish to show you.
Chu-wol.
Your Grace?
Your Grace.
Your Grace…
Quench your thirst.
You look a mess.
Your Grace.
Do not worry.
I did not say a word.
They may threaten my life,
but I will not say a word,
so do not worry, Your Grace.
Do not worry.
I will get you out of here.
Right now, Your Grace?
Yes.
I appreciate
all that you have done for me.
Your Grace.
Your Grace…
This is the only way
you can get out of here, Chu-wol.
What's taking him so long?
It's scary out here.
He always does whatever he wants.
Your Majesty.
Isn't that a Cheoyong mask?
It is.
It is said to ward off evil.
It also symbolizes
long life and abundance.
Are you going to dance
the Cheoyongmu right now?
I am thinking of performing it
at the banquet
celebrating my grandmother's
seventieth year.
She used to very much enjoy
the Cheoyongmu I performed
when I was little.
Why did you want to see me at this hour?
I want you to be the first
to watch me dance.
Me?
Yes.
Will you watch?
Okay.
Though I did watch you dance before.
This might be
the last time
I get to watch that dance.
-Who are you?
-No, stop! Wait!
You crazy fool!
I'm pretty good with a knife too.
I'm a chef. It's the same thing as a cook.
My gosh!
As of this moment,
the chief royal cook of the royal kitchen
is Ji-young of the Yeon family.
You're not at all
the kind of man that I like.
Let me see.
Hide behind me.
Right here.
There is something on yours as well.
It's beautiful. Look at the colors.
Stay as you are. Just for a while.
Just for a while.
Stay here just a while.
I missed you so much.
Was this always such a sad dance?
Yi Jang-gyun.
You bastard!
Control yourself.
Your Highness, what are we to make
of his apprehension?
It means the time has come.
Look over there.
Father?
Father.
Who is that senile old woman?
She is our finishing touch.
Is she the Internal Princess Consort?
Pardon?
Are you saying that woman is the mother
of the deposed Queen Yeon?
That is so.
She is His Majesty's maternal grandmother,
Internal Princess Consort Sim
from Goheung.
She had something very important
in her possession.
Inside that doll
is the bloodstained garment
the deposed queen wore
when she was poisoned to death.
Your Highness.
At last.
It is done.
Soon,
the whole truth will come to light.
On the day of
the Grand Royal Queen Dowager's banquet,
the tyrant
will lose control
and let loose his madness,
and the palace will be drenched in blood.
How was it?
It didn't feel like this last time.
But today,
you looked cool.
Oh, I'm fine.
The breeze is cold at night.
I must ask you something.
Do you still
wish to find Mangunrok and return?
Of course. Why do you ask?
I do not
want you to leave.
Wherever that may be.
Do you finally believe
I'm from the future?
I could tell
you were not a person of this time.
How?
The day you made gochojang bibinbap.
The day you prepared oat sheen.
The day you served me doenjang paasta.
I felt it all along…
that you were not from this place.
Then you knew all along,
and you still mistreated me like that?
Mistreated?
What are you talking about?
I don't believe this.
Just find me Mangunrok already.
Do you really wish to find that book?
Wait.
Have you not been looking for it
all this time?
I am sure I will find it soon.
However…
I did not want to look for it.
Your Majesty.
Be my companion.
-That's just not--
-I mean it.
If you become my companion,
every morning,
I will make you bibinbap.
That was the moment
that I thought maybe it wouldn't be so bad
even if I didn't go back
to my time and my world.
BON APPÉTIT, YOUR MAJESTY
In return, promise me something.
Promise me that you won't be a tyrant.
Today marks the beginning of a new Joseon.
A special guest will be coming tonight.
The chief royal cook
was taken by a band of rebels.
You must be safe.
Today!
I will set everything right.
Is there really no way to stop this?
Subtitle translation by: Jennifer Jean Lim